Applause Beyond our solar system, there are planets that gravitate around other stars. They are called exoplanets. Exoplanets because they are outside the solar system. As you can imagine, it is really difficult to detect them because they are very far from us and yet regularly astronomers tell us that they have discovered new exoplanets. There is even a recent study that suggests
that among all the exoplanets that must exist in our galaxy,
There could be 20 billion,
which may have liquid water on their surface
and thus provide a potentially interesting environment for life.
Do you realize?
20 billion?
If we want to study the criteria of the habitability of a planet,
We're going to look at four criteria.
which must be brought together for this study to be a success.
The first criterion is that the planet is at the right distance from the star. In reality, the image you have on the screen is a drawing of exoplanets. Because they are far too far away, we cannot see this level of detail. But what the artist wanted to represent is a planet in the zone of habitability of the star, that is, the surface of which the temperature would be the right one for the water to exist in the liquid state for a long time. Closer to us, in the solar system, there are also planets that can inform us about habitability. So of course,
who will run this program automatically the next day,
And so on.
This is a pretty great and quite successful example of collaborative work,
And I'm lucky, with a few colleagues,
the help of the CNES, to participate from here, in Toulouse.
Curiosity is also equipped with a small drill, a small drill.
I'll zoom in on this photo.
... in Toulouse. Curiosity is also equipped with a small drill, a small drill. I will zoom in on this photo. We can see the hole that was dug into the rock, which turns out to be a clay, so a rock that formed in the presence of water too. And we notice that the powder of this rock has a different color, it is greyish, it is different from the color of the martian surface that is red. We can see also the marks that the laser left by sampling this rock powder. And well by gathering all the results of all these instruments and the knowledge of all these
So, ladies and gentlemen, please,
Keep getting drunk with curiosity.