Applause
Beyond our solar system, there are planets that orbit other stars.
They are called exoplanets, exoplanets because they are outside the solar system.
As you can imagine,
It's really difficult to detect them because they are very far from us.
Yet, regularly,
astronomers
they announce that they have discovered new exoplanets.
There is even a recent study.
who suggests
that among all the exoplanets that must exist in our galaxy,
There could be 20 billion.
and thus to offer a potentially interesting environment for life. Do you realize, 20 billion?
Well, if we want to study the criteria for a planet's habitability,
We will focus on four criteria that must be met for this study to be a success.
The first criterion is that the planet is the right distance from the star.
So actually the image you see on the screen is a drawing of an exoplanet.
because they are too far away, we cannot see this level of detail.
But what the artist intended to depict is a planet in the habitable zone of the star.
That is, the surface on which the temperature would be right for water to remain in a liquid state for a sufficient amount of time.
Closer to us, within our solar system, there are also planets that can tell us about habitability.
So of course, today, to our knowledge,
There is only one that is habitable and inhabited.