Exoplanets because they're outside the solar system. As you can imagine, it's really hard to detect them because they're so far away from us, and yet astronomers regularly tell us that they've discovered new exoplanets.
That among all the exoplanets that should exist in our galaxy,
There could be 20 billion.
likely to have liquid water on their surface
and thus provide a potentially interesting environment for life.
You know what I mean?
20 billion?
If we want to study the criteria for the habitability of a planet,
We're going to look at four criteria
The Commission is also working on a proposal for a directive on the protection of workers' rights and the rights of workers.
The first criterion is that the planet is at the right distance from the star, that is, the surface of which the temperature is preceded by the right jet of measurement for the water to remain in the desert for a few months. But because they are far too far away, you can't see that level of detail. But what the artist wanted to represent is a planet in the habitable zone of the star, that is, the surface of which the temperature is preceded by the right jet of measurement for the water to remain in the desert for a few months. But now, in the solar
which will automatically run this program the next day,
And so on and so forth.
It's a pretty great example and a pretty good example of collaborative work.
And I'm lucky, with a few colleagues,
The Commission has already decided to take part in the programme.
Curiosity also has a small drill, a small drill bit.
I'm going to zoom in on this photo.
And then you see that the powder in this rock has a different color, it's grayish, it's different from the color of the Martian surface which is red. You can also see the few marks that the laser left in the rock sample, which turns out to be clay, so a rock that formed in the presence of water too. And you notice that the powder in this rock has a different color, it's grayish, it's different from the color of the Martian surface which is red. So you can see a few laser prints that were dug in this rock sample
So ladies and gentlemen, please,
Keep getting drunk with curiosity.